William Temple Franklin Papers 1775-1819 Mss.B.F86
American Philosophical Society
- William Temple Franklin Papers, 1775-1790; Mss.B.F86; 4.5 lin. feet
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 October 29; ALS, 1p.; Bart, Sir H. Morres. Amboise
    Acknowledges, with thanks, receipt of mustard.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 October 29; ALS, 1p.; de la Roche-Tilhac, Abbé Poncelin
    Acknowledges, with thanks, the receipt of information concerning United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 October 31; ALS, 2p.; Griffitts, Samuel Powel. Montpelier
    Friendly inquiries.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 October; ALS, 2p.; Vaughan, John
    Expressing satisfaction with the country and his intention of remaining. Buys property in Berkley County [Va.] of General [Charles] Lee. Laments death of latter. Rumors of peace with England. National spirit pervades the country. Gaieties in Philadelphia.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 October; ALS, 4p.; Bache, Sarah
    Personal news and items. Gov. [William] Franklin sailed [for England] on the 18th of September.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 4; ALS, 2p.; Quétant, Antoine-François, 1733-1823
    Acknowledging, with thanks, courtesies shown l'Abbé de la Roche-Tilhac.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 12 and 15; ALS, 4p. and 3p.; Vaughan, John
    Portraying sentiments entertained in the United States toward England. Discusses peace terms. Local government.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 17; ALS, 1p.; Newenham, Sir Edward. Marseilles
    Proffering the gift of a horse.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 18; ALS, 1p.; Frank, J. Montrouge
    Recommending a groom.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 19; ALS, 2p.; Le Veillard fils, Louis
    Inquiring about the tobacco trade in New England.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 25; ALS, 3p.; Ridley, Matthew
    Information regarding the tobacco trade in the United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 28; ALS, 3p.; Manson, George Jr.
    Giving an account of cures effected by M. Bonsart at the Invalides.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 November 29; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Ridley, Matthew
    Requesting him to forward two packages.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 3; A.L.; de Chabanon, Chevalier
    Letter of thanks.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 3; ALS, 1p.; Bache, Sarah
    Sends squirrel skins.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 4; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; De Beche and Graff. St. Sauveur
    Sending lace ruffles and patterns.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 5; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Regarding rumors of peace. If Dr. Franklin wishes to convey the news to America, he can have a fast-sailing brig at sea at twenty-four hours notice.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 8; ALS, 1p.; Newenham, Sir Edward. Marseilles
    Requesting letters of introduction to influential people in Geneva. Leghorn and Florence.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 8; ALS, 1p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Requesting a pass for Mr. Bird.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 9; ALS, 2p.; Barclay, Thomas
    Inquiring as to the advisability of sending supplies to the United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 11; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Chardon, Daniel-Marc-Antoine
    Arranging an interview.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 12; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Adams, John
    Inviting him to dine with him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 13; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Pechigny, Mme. Devillier
    Returning money lent.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 16; ALS, 1p.; Moylan, James.
    Regarding money taken in mistake by a courier.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 17; ALS, 6p.; Le Veillard fils, Louis
    Inquires about the risk attending the sending of vessels to the United States during the peace negotiations.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 17; ALS, 3p.; Mumford, Gurdon S.
    Answer to inquiry about boxes of seeds.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 20; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Giving cost of his vessel. Many wise people doubt a general peace. He thinks it clear and will govern himself accordingly.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 25; ALS, 1p.; Watson, Elkanah Jr
    Soliciting aid for Captain Hardy. Request a suit of old clothes of Benjamin Franklin's with which to dress a wax figure of him made by Madame [Patience] Wright and to be set up in his study.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 25; ALS, 3p.; Ridley, Matthew
    Replying to inquiries regarding trade in the United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 28; ALS, 1p.; Bancroft, Edward
    Acknowledging, with thanks, receipt of the certificate.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 29; ALS, 3p.; England, Major Richard
    Soliciting Franklin's influence to obtain permission for him to act in his military capacity, pending an exchange of prisoners.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782 December 30; CIV, 147.; Newenham, Sir Edward. Marseilles
    Rejoicing upon the full establishment of American Independence.
  - to W.T. Franklin, 1778] Dec 30; A.N.S. 1p.; Jauge, Theodore
    Sending four certificates to be signed by Dr. Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Alexander, William
    Asks him to tell Madame Helvétius that "one coach full of Alexanders will wait on her Wednesday". The postponed St. Germain ball will be on Thursday.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Alexander, William. Auteuil
    Lends his horse with great pleasure and wishes to borrow his carriage to take Amantiné, the Italian singer, from Paris to Auteuil and back.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 1p.; Bache, Benjamin Franklin
    Apologizes for not writing; has not forgotten all his kindnesses.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 2p.; Bancroft, Edward
    Asks for a passport for Peter Fowler who is to take a letter to Mr. [William] Hodgson.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 1p.; Bancroft, Edward
    As his sword is broken he asks for the loan of one of William Temple Franklin's.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 1p.; Bancroft, Edward
    Invites him and his grandfather to dinner to meet Mr. [Thomas] Walpole and his son.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 1p.; Bancroft, Edward
    Expects him for dinner; wishes to borrow two bottles of claret and one of sherry.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; A.N.S. 1p.; Bancroft, Edward
    Encloses Mr. [Samuel] Wharton's bill with his receipt.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1782; A.L. 2p.; Barclay, Thomas
    Sends a letter to Mr. [John] Penn, now in Paris; [Capt. Joshua] Barney went to sea on the 17th; asks for news of the cartel; if the vessel does not arrive soon, the British will have to be sent to Dinan, then the commander of the cartel will go to St. Malo; let him know any important news as quickly as possible; can save the United States much money since there is a considerable difference between peace and war freights.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; A.N. in 3d P. 1p.; Brillon, Mme
    Requesting him to remind his Grandfather of his promise to come and take tea with her and play a game of chess.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 2p.; Cabaret, -----
    Wishes to know what sized paper Franklin wants.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Chalut, Mme de
    Has received a case for him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 1p.; Fox, George
    Introducing Mr. [William] Rawle.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; A.L. 1p.; Grand, Henry
    The bill for £180 has been placed to Mr. Hodgson's credit.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; A.L. in 3d P. 1p.; Hazlehurst, Isaac
    Asks that the bills, if accepted, be returned.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; L. in 3d P. 1p.; Lafayette, Marie Joseph Paul Yves, marquis de, 1757-1834
    Asking him to receive M. de Sai[l]ly and assist him with his device; intends giving M. de Sai[l]ly letters of recommendation to America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 1p.; de la Roche-Tilhac, Abbé Poncelin
    Sends two copies of his book, one for him, the other for the illustrious Mr. [Benjamin] Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Du Portail, Louis le Bègue
    Inquires when the "Washington" sails, as he wishes to send some letters to America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 1p.; Ridley, Matthew
    Invitation to dinner for Dr. Franklin and himself.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; A.L. 1p.; Williams, Mrs. Mariamne
    Inviting him to their house at St. Germain.
  - to William Temple Franklin, ca.1782.; ALS, 2p.; Wright, Joseph
    Will not be able to leave Paris as every place was taken, therefore returns Mr. [Jonathan] Williams, [Jr.]'s letter; asks permission to make another copy of Benjamin Franklin's picture. Mr. [Caleb] Whitefoord took the last one he made.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 1; ALS, 2p.; Bancroft, Edward
    Sends letter referred to by Dr. Ingen Housz; is much displeased at the latter's distrust of his veracity.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 2; ALS, 5p.; Newenham, Sir Edward. Marseilles
    Tells of his sympathy and support of the American cause in Ireland; showed it on several occasions; appeared in deep mourning in the Irish Parliament on the death of Gen. [Richard] Montgomery. Balked the attempt of the British Government to secure an address of support from the citizens of Dublin during the war; the people overwhelmingly opposed to it. The British Government feared to draft many troops out of Ireland; only 2,000 out of the 13,000 troops in Ireland were sent to America. Predicts a great future for the United States. Recommends two of his friends for appointment as Consular Agents. Recalls the address of Congress to the people of Ireland signed in August, 1775, and forwarded to him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 6; ALS, 2p.; Barclay, Thomas
    Will take all the necessary steps to billet the British prisoners in France. Proposes to send back the American prisoners to America in a cartel. Is superintending the loading of public goods and supplies for America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 7; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Moore and Co.
    Sends a list of the prisoners taken by the "Buccaneer" and the "Revolution," which they suppose will be the last they shall have the pleasure of sending, being told that the preliminaries for a general peace are signed.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 8; L.S. 1p.; Jonathan Nesbitt and Co.
    Inquiring about a bill of F[rancis] Hopkinson on the United States Commissioners, in favor of John Sparhawk.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 9; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Repaying 10 louis loaned to Capt. [Daniel] McNeill by William Temple Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 16; ALS, 3P.; Barrington, Richard. Abbeville
    Is a son of the late Gen. Barrington and served for a time as an ensign in the 3d Regiment of Foot Guards. Has severed his connection with the English army and is living with his mother in France. Wishes to obtain employment in the United States army and offers his services.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 21; ALS, 3p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Everyone in a state of suspense as to whether there is to be peace or war. Asks to be given a hint in time. Applies for commissions for two brigs owned by him and Sam[uel] White.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 22; ALS, 2p.; Caffiéri, Jean Jacques
    Hopes he will be chosen to execute a statue of Dr. Franklin, or some monument to commemorate the signing of peace between England and the United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 23; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Renews his request for commissions or passports for two brigs, the "Olive" and the " Hetty." Current report that a general peace was signed on the 19th.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 24; ALS, 1p.; Hodgson, Williams
    Inquiring about the freighting of a ship, the " Weeren firenden," at l'orient by the Minister of Marine.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 24; L.S. 2p.; Barclay, Thomas
    Relating to shipment by him of public supplies to America.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 Janaury 25.; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Introducing his friend, [Major] Samuel White.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January 25; ALS, 1p.; de la Roche-Tilhac, Abbé Poncelin
    Thanking him for sending his "little American almanac" to the United States. Is going to publish a second edition.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 January.; ALS, 4p.; Chaumont, Le Ray de, fils
    Refers to Mlles, Brillon and comments sarcastically on the accident to the Duke de Chartres. Tells of his stag and fox hunts.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 February 2; ALS, 1p.; Jauge, Theodore
    Introducing M. Michel, of Beauvais.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 February 4.; ALS, 3p.; Carmichael, William. Madrid
    Has learned from Mr. [Robert R.] Livingston and Mr. [Robert] Morris that bills had been remitted for arrears of his salary. Is in a very difficult situation owing to lack of funds. Will be obliged to draw on Dr. Franklin for money due Mr. [Francis] Cabarras. Expects Marquis Lafayette to visit the city; will be a great consolation to him. Comments on the treaty with Great Britain and inquires about Dr. [Edward] Bancroft and Mr. [Francis M.] Dana.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 February 5; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Enclosing two drafts.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 February 6.; ALS, 1p.; Carmichael, William. Madrid
    Introducing Mr. [Diego] Gardoqui as his particular friend.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 February 6; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Requesting passports for American vessels at Bordeaux, Nantes and I'Orient.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 February 11; ALS, 3p.; Le Veillard fils, Louis
    Tells of a plan by which he is to enter as junior partner into a large firm which is to establish a branch house in New England.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 February 13; ALS, 1p.; Alexander, William
    Enclosing a letter to be delivered to M. d'Aguesseau. The estates [in Grenada] were sequestrated. If [Thomas] Walpole's claims are unjust, he can ruin the estates in three months before the English get possession.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 February 14; ALS, 2p.; Chanorié, -----
    Enclosing a letter received for Dr. Franklin. Requests cards for Mme. and Mlles. de Villarceaux for a ball to be given by William Temple Franklin.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 February 15; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Requesting an explanation of the 23d Article of the Treaty of Peace regarding the latitude of the Canary Islands.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 February 18; ALS, 2p.; Le Roy, Jean Baptiste
    Asking for information about trade with the United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 February 22; ALS, 1p.; Lherbelle, -----
    With reference to squirrel skins he has prepared, for making a furcoat.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 February 28; L.S. 2p.; John Torris and Wante. Dunkerque
    Requesting passport for the brig "Franklin" and the brigantine "Hazard" bound from Dunkerque to Philadelphia.
  - to William Temple Franklin., 1783 March 4; A.N.S. 1p.; Raibaud A
    Has received a box for him; will try to pass it at Calais.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 5; ALS, 4p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    With reference to the purchase of certain articles for him. Remarks on the Treaty of Peace and the political situation in England.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 5; ALS, 1p.; White, Samuel
    Sends letter by Mr. [Charles] Storer, to be forwarded to Nantes and St. Germain. Items of news about events in London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 6; L.S. 1p.; Madlin, ------
    Relating to repairs made to a cabriolet.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 6; ALS, 1p.; Bachelier, Jean Jacques
    Accepting his invitation to dinner.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 8; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Graff, P. B
    Sending cambric ruffles made for him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 8; ALS, 2p.; Nogaret, François-Félix
    Invites him to the dedication of the new temple of the "R. L. du Patriotisme."
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 13; L.S. 2p.; John Torris and Wante. Dunkerque
    Relating to a passport for their brig "Franklin." Request a list of drugs which would find ready sale in the United States. Offer to sell a newly built vessel, "L'Aigle," of fourteen guns, to Congress.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 13; L.S. 2p.; Schaffer, John
    Assures him that the bill of exchange which he gave him will be paid.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 19; ALS, 2p.; Grand, Henry
    Sending copy of Dr. Franklin's banking account.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 22; L.S. 1p.; Barclay, Thomas
    Relating to prize-money claimed by the "Alliance" and Commodore [John Paul] Jones's squadron.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 22; A.L. 5p.; Le Veillard fils, Louis
    Explains his plan for starting in business in America. Refers to trade relations between England and the United States and comments on William Temple Franklin's desire to settle permanently in France. Gives directions for shipping to him a keg of powder.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 22; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Refers to receipt of two drafts of Dr. Franklin on Nathaniel Braley and Frederick Buscalier. Remarks on French export commerce to the United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 26; ALS, 2p.; Tourville, -----
    Relating to the purchase of a horse for him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 March 26; ALS, 2p.; Storer, Charles
    Refers to his visit to Mme. St. Leger; is ignorant of Parisian customs and asks advice how to act. Encloses patterns for frocks for inspection as to the most fashionable one.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 April 1; A.N.S. 1p.; Williams, Mrs. Mariamne
    Sends back the carriage by her father.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 April 2; ALS, 2p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Requests him to read the letter he has written to Dr. Franklin and to reply to it.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 April 10; Carmichael, William, Madrid
    Tells of the visit of Comte d'Estaing and Marquis Lafayette to Madrid; is pleased they were witnesses of his conduct and mode of life. Will soon close his public accounts and send them to Mr. [John] Jay
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 15; ALS, 2p.; Fox, George
    Capt. [Gustavus] Cunningham will not sail until the end of the month. Offers to carry the Definitive Treaty to America. Will also take any messages or letters Mr. or Mrs. [John] Jay or Mr.[John] Adams may wish to send by him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 17; ALS, 2p.; Vaughan, John
    Learns that peace was proclaimed by Congress on the 11th and the British King's health drunk at the French Minister's. Peace well received; expectations of a liberal commercial treaty with England. Dr. Franklin's return anxiously awaited by Mr. and Mrs. [Richard] Bache.
  - to William Temple Franklin, [1783] May 18; N. in 3d P. 1p.; d'Estaing, Comte
    Inviting him to a dinner at which Mme. la Marquise Lafayette will be present.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 21; ALS, 1p.; Kéralio, Agathon Guynement, chevalier de
    Requests three of the commemorative medals of American independence, one for the library of the Royal Military School and the other two for Marquis de Timbrune and Baron de Moyria.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 22; ALS, 1p.; Kéralio, Agathon Guynement, chevalier de
    Received the three medals and expresses his thanks.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 25; ALS, 1p.; Madlin, -------
    Renews demand for payment of his account.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 25; ALS, 1p.; Le Veillard fils, Louis
    With reference to a horse he is sending to him.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 27; ALS, 2p.; Ross, John Philadelphia
    Introducing Mr. Waring, of South Carolina, who goes to Paris to complete his education.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 May 29; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Hesse Mrs
    Inviting him to call.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 1; ALS, 1p.; Laneuville, Louis Pierre Panot Lombart, chevalier de, 1744-ca.1800
    Invitation to dine.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 2; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Graff P. B
    Invites him to call and see his new stock of Valenciennes ruffles, vestcoats, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 4; ALS, 1p.; Loreilhe Z.
    Requesting that letters for Mrs. Hudson "the Lavaux," an American lady in a convent in this neighborhood, be forwarded for delivery to Barclay, Moylan and Co., of l'Orient.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 5; ALS, 2p.; Fox, George.
    Is about to take passage with Capt. Hoops on the "Nancy" which is ready to sail for Philadelphia.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 6; A.L. 4p.; Vaughan, Benjamin
    Shipment of four boxes containing various articles for him and Dr. Franklin, Mrs. [John] Jay, Duke de Chaulnes, etc.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 13; ALS, 1p.; Elphinston, James
    Introducing John Paterson, of the firm of William Heines G. Keith and Co., of Ostend.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 13; ALS, 2p.; Drummond, James
    As a former school-fellow, introduces and recommends his friend John Paterson.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 16; ALS, 1p.; De St. Fond, Barthélemy Faujas
    Inviting him to dine at the house of a friend who wishes to show him a machine he has invented.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 24; A.L. 4p.; Le Veillard fils, Louis
    Request to send him his keg of powder and order a Marlborough suit for him. Banters him on his hopeless suit for the hand of a certain young lady [Mlle. Brillon].
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 24; L.S. 1p.; Watson, Elkanah Jr
    Is forwarding embroidered handkerchiefs.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 25; ALS, 1p.; de Fontenet, -----
    Requests a reply to an inquiry from the Prince de Deux-Ponts about trade between certain German States and the United States.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 26; N. in 3d P. 1p.; Darcel, -----
    Request to meet him at the Custom House, to be present at opening of boxes shipped to him from London.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June 30; ALS, 3p.; Fox, George. Lisbon
    Tells of his arrival at that port and gives his impressions of the Portuguese capital and its people.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 June; ALS, 4p.; Vaughan, Samuel Jr. Strasbourg
    Refers to the friendship shown him by Prof. [Jacques Reinhold] Spielmann. Tells of Hoffmann's antecedents and business career.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 July 2; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.
    Requests a certificate, signed by Dr. Franklin, as to the limits fixed by the Treaty of Peace, to decide the validity of captures at sea.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 July 3; L.S. 1p.; Hudet, -----
    His promise to reward him for service rendered as driver of a hire carriage.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 July 3; ALS, 1p.; Capitaine, -----
    Regrets his inability to be present at the celebration in Dr. Franklin' house of the anniversary of American Independence.
  - to William Temple Franklin, 1783 July 8; ALS, 1p.; Williams, Jonathan Jr.